[
    {
        "id": 1,
        "question": "What does primary memory refer to?",
        "options": [
            "a) RAM",
            "b) ROM",
            "c) HDD",
            "d) None of the above"
        ],
        "correct": "a) RAM"
    },
    {
        "id": 2,
        "question": "The size and layout of the case is called?",
        "options": [
            "a) From Factor",
            "b) Form Factor",
            "c) Rack",
            "d) None of the above"
        ],
        "correct": "b) Form Factor"
    },
    {
        "id": 3,
        "question": "Which of the following is not the form factor of CPU Case?",
        "options": [
            "a) ATX",
            "b) Mini ATX",
            "c) Micro ATX",
            "d) None of the above"
        ],
        "correct": "c) Micro ATX"
    },
    {
        "id": 4,
        "question": "PSU Stands For?",
        "options": [
            "a) Processing Speed Unit",
            "b) Power Supply Unit",
            "c) Power Supplied Unit",
            "d) None of the above"
        ],
        "correct": "c) Power Supplied Unit"
    },
    {
        "id": 5,
        "question": "Cables in PSU are not detachable.",
        "options": [
            "a) True",
            "b) False",
            "c) Depends",
            "d) None of the above"
        ],
        "correct": "a) True"
    },
    {
        "id": 6,
        "question": "Mother Board is the main PCB. PCB stands for?",
        "options": [
            "a) Power Control Bus",
            "b) Printed Circuit Board",
            "c) Processor Control Block",
            "d) None of the above"
        ],
        "correct": "b) Printed Circuit Board"
    },
    {
        "id": 7,
        "question": "Which Chipset has Direct connection to CPU?",
        "options": [
            "a) NBC",
            "b) SBC",
            "c) BIOS",
            "d) None of the above"
        ],
        "correct": "c) BIOS"
    },
    {
        "id": 8,
        "question": "Which is the faster component?",
        "options": [
            "a) PCl",
            "b) RAM",
            "c) 1 GHz is equivalent to ?",
            "d) None of the above"
        ],
        "correct": "c) 1 GHz is equivalent to ?"
    },
    {
        "id": 9,
        "question": "1 GHz is equivalent to?",
        "options": [
            "a) IOOOHz",
            "b) 1 Million Hz",
            "c) 1 Billion Hz",
            "d) None of the above"
        ],
        "correct": "c) 1 Billion Hz"
    },
    {
        "id": 10,
        "question": "LGA and PGA are type of?",
        "options": [
            "a) RAM Slots",
            "b) CPU Socket",
            "c) CPU Case",
            "d) None of the above"
        ],
        "correct": "b) CPU Socket"
    },
    {
        "id": 11,
        "question": "LGA stands for?",
        "options": [
            "a) Live Graphic Array",
            "b) Linear Grid Array",
            "c) Land Grid Array",
            "d) None of the above"
        ],
        "correct": "c) Land Grid Array"
    },
    {
        "id": 12,
        "question": "Which is not a example of drive?",
        "options": [
            "a) Floppy",
            "b) Hard Drive",
            "c) RAM",
            "d) None of the above"
        ],
        "correct": "c) RAM"
    },
    {
        "id": 13,
        "question": "CPU executes sequence of instruction called?",
        "options": [
            "a) Programs",
            "b) Processes",
            "c) Files",
            "d) Arrays"
        ],
        "correct": "b) Processes"
    },
    {
        "id": 14,
        "question": "ZIF stands for?",
        "options": [
            "a) Zero initialization force",
            "b) Zero Intensive Force",
            "c) Zero Insertion force",
            "d) None of the above"
        ],
        "correct": "c) Zero Insertion force"
    },
    {
        "id": 15,
        "question": "While the CPU is executing one step of the program, the other instructions and data are stored in",
        "options": [
            "a) NBC",
            "b) RAM",
            "c) Cache Memory",
            "d) HDD"
        ],
        "correct": "c) Cache Memory"
    },
    {
        "id": 16,
        "question": "Which is the faster cpu architecture",
        "options": [
            "a) X86",
            "b) X64",
            "c) X128",
            "d) registry"
        ],
        "correct": "b) X64"
    },
    {
        "id": 17,
        "question": "Processor runs at less than the rated speed to save power and produces less heat Commonly used in Laptops and Mobile devices.",
        "options": [
            "a) CPU Clocking",
            "b) Under Volt",
            "c) CPU Throttle",
            "d) Under Clocking"
        ],
        "correct": "b) Under Volt"
    },
    {
        "id": 18,
        "question": "Choose the Secondary Memories.",
        "options": [
            "a) HDD",
            "b) SSD",
            "c) Magnetic Tapes",
            "d) None of the above"
        ],
        "correct": "c) Magnetic Tapes"
    },
    {
        "id": 19,
        "question": "Full Form of EEPROM?",
        "options": [
            "a) EPROM",
            "b) EEPROM",
            "c) PEROM",
            "d) PROM"
        ],
        "correct": "b) EEPROM"
    },
    {
        "id": 20,
        "question": "Choose the Types of Ram.",
        "options": [
            "a) SDRAM",
            "b) DRAM",
            "c) SRAM",
            "d) None of the above"
        ],
        "correct": "c) SRAM"
    },
    {
        "id": 17,
        "question": "It is used to enhance performance of the CPU where multiple pieces of code would be executing simultaneously on each pipeline.",
        "options": [
            "HyperLooping",
            "Hyper Threading",
            "Multi Threading",
            "Multi Tasking"
        ],
        "correct": "Hyper Threading"
    },
    {
        "id": 18,
        "question": "Makes processor work at a faster speed than normal but can result in damage to the CPU.",
        "options": [
            "Turbo Boost",
            "Over-Clocking",
            "Multi Threading",
            "CPU Throttle"
        ],
        "correct": "Over-Clocking"
    },
    {
        "id": 19,
        "question": "Processor runs at less than the rated speed to save power and produce less heat. Commonly used in laptops and mobile devices.",
        "options": [
            "CPU Clocking",
            "CPU Throttling",
            "Under Volt",
            "Under Clocking"
        ],
        "correct": "Under Clocking"
    },
    {
        "id": 20,
        "question": "Choose the Secondary Memories.",
        "options": [
            "HDD",
            "SSD",
            "Magnetic Tapes",
            "Cache"
        ],
        "correct": "HDD"
    },
    {
        "id": 21,
        "question": "Full form of EEPROM?",
        "options": [],
        "correct": "Electrically Erasable Programmable Read-Only Memory"
    },
    {
        "id": 22,
        "question": "Choose the Types of RAM.",
        "options": [
            "SDRAM",
            "VRAM",
            "DRAM",
            "SRAM"
        ],
        "correct": "SDRAM"
    },
    {
        "id": 23,
        "question": "In the hierarchy of memory which comes first?",
        "options": [
            "RAM",
            "Cache",
            "HDD",
            "SSD"
        ],
        "correct": "Cache"
    },
    {
        "id": 24,
        "question": "Choose the Types of ROM.",
        "options": [
            "EPROM",
            "EEPROM",
            "PEROM",
            "PROM"
        ],
        "correct": "EPROM"
    },
    {
        "id": 25,
        "question": "DDR Stands For?",
        "options": [
            "Dynamic Data Rate",
            "Dual Data Rating",
            "Double Data Rate",
            "Dynamic Data Restore"
        ],
        "correct": "Double Data Rate"
    },
    {
        "id": 26,
        "question": "SD RAM Stands For?",
        "options": [
            "Simple Durable Random Access Memory",
            "Synchronous Dynamic Random Access Memory",
            "Sequential Dynamic Random Access Memory",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "correct": "Synchronous Dynamic Random Access Memory"
    },
    {
        "id": 27,
        "question": "What is the common number of pins in DDR 2 RAM?",
        "options": [
            "188",
            "210",
            "240",
            "320"
        ],
        "correct": "240"
    },
    {
        "id": 28,
        "question": "DIMM and SIMM are types of?",
        "options": [
            "ROM",
            "CPU",
            "RAM",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "correct": "RAM"
    },
    {
        "id": 29,
        "question": "SRAM is used as?",
        "options": [
            "ROM",
            "Dynamic Memory",
            "Virtual Memory",
            "Cache Memory"
        ],
        "correct": "Cache Memory"
    },
    {
        "id": 30,
        "question": "RAID Uses?",
        "options": [
            "Flash Drives",
            "Inexpensive Disks",
            "Fast Storage",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "correct": "Inexpensive Disks"
    },
    {
        "id": 31,
        "question": "RAID Stands for?",
        "options": [
            "Redundant Array of In-durable Disks",
            "Redundant Array of Independent Disks",
            "Regular Array of Inexpensive Disk",
            "Redundant Arrangement of Independent Disk"
        ],
        "correct": "Redundant Array of Independent Disks"
    },
    {
        "id": 32,
        "question": "Choose the correct answer. PCI is a?",
        "options": [
            "32 Bit Expansion Slot",
            "64 Bit Expansion Slot",
            "Inexpensive Disk",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "correct": "32 Bit Expansion Slot"
    },
    {
        "id": 33,
        "question": "AGP Stands For?",
        "options": [
            "Advanced Graphic Peripheral",
            "Added Graphic Port",
            "Advanced Graphics Port",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "correct": "Advanced Graphics Port"
    },
    {
        "id": 34,
        "question": "The speed of a hard drive is measured in?",
        "options": [
            "Revolution Per Minute",
            "Rotation Per Minute"
        ],
        "correct": "Rotation Per Minute"
    },
    {
        "id": 35,
        "question": "Which of the following statements are true?",
        "options": [
            "SSD are Faster Drives",
            "SSD are Cheaper",
            "SSD uses low power",
            "Data can be easily recovered"
        ],
        "correct": "SSD are Faster Drives"
    },
    {
        "id": 36,
        "question": "Which computer component contains all the circuitry necessary for all components or devices to communicate with each other?",
        "options": [
            "MotherBoard",
            "HardDrive",
            "Expansion Slots",
            "Adapter Card"
        ],
        "correct": "MotherBoard"
    },
    {
        "id": 37,
        "question": "Which Case type is typically used for servers?",
        "options": [
            "Mid Tower",
            "Mini Tower",
            "Full Tower",
            "Desktop"
        ],
        "correct": "Full Tower"
    },
    {
        "id": 38,
        "question": "What is the most reliable way for users to buy the correct RAM to upgrade a computer?",
        "options": [
            "Buy RAM that is the same color as the memory sockets on the motherboard.",
            "Ensure that the RAM is compatible with the peripherals installed on the motherboard.",
            "Ensure that the RAM chip is the same size as the ROM chip.",
            "Check the motherboard manual or manufacturer's website."
        ],
        "correct": "Check the motherboard manual or manufacturer's website."
    },
    {
        "id": 39,
        "question": "Which two connectors are used to connect external peripherals? (Choose two.)",
        "options": [
            "Mole",
            "PS2",
            "PATA",
            "USB"
        ],
        "correct": "PS2, USB"
    },
    {
        "id": 40,
        "question": "A field technician has been asked to install a wireless 802.11g NIC in a computer, but is unsure about the expansion slots available. Which port should the technician use? (Choose two.)",
        "options": [
            "PCIe",
            "SCSI",
            "AGP",
            "PCI"
        ],
        "correct": "PCIe, PCI"
    },
    {
        "id": 41,
        "question": "Which component helps cool the CPU? (Choose two.)",
        "options": [
            "Heat Sink",
            "Fan",
            "Floppy",
            "RAID"
        ],
        "correct": "Heat Sink, Fan"
    },
    {
        "id": 42,
        "question": "What was the original name for a monitor?",
        "options": [
            "Video Display Unit",
            "Liquid Crystal Display",
            "Cathode Ray Tube",
            "Optical Display Unit"
        ],
        "correct": "Cathode Ray Tube"
    },
    {
        "id": 43,
        "question": "Which power problem is an overvoltage condition that lasts for up to several seconds?",
        "options": [
            "Spike",
            "Surge",
            "Sag",
            "Blackout"
        ],
        "correct": "Surge"
    },
    {
        "id": 44,
        "question": "Which of the following memory types has the smallest form factor?",
        "options": [
            "RIMM",
            "DIMM",
            "MicroDIMM",
            "SODIMM"
        ],
        "correct": "MicroDIMM"
    },
    {
        "id": 45,
        "question": "Which of the following hard drives has the best shock resistance?",
        "options": [
            "IDE",
            "SSD",
            "NAS",
            "SATA"
        ],
        "correct": "SSD"
    },
    {
        "id": 46,
        "question": "Which device protects computing devices from power dips and blackouts?",
        "options": [
            "UPS",
            "Surge Suppressor",
            "Surge Protector",
            "GPS"
        ],
        "correct": "UPS"
    },
    {
        "id": 47,
        "question": "What companies dominate the chipset market? (Select Two.)",
        "options": [
            "AMD",
            "INTEL",
            "Nvidia",
            "Dell"
        ],
        "correct": "AMD, INTEL"
    },
    {
        "id": 48,
        "question": "What provides the illumination for LCD monitors?",
        "options": [
            "Backlights",
            "Inverter",
            "Lamp",
            "LCD panel"
        ],
        "correct": "Backlights"
    },
    {
        "id": 49,
        "question": "Which level of RAID refers to disk Mirroring with block stripping?",
        "options": [
            "RAID 10",
            "RAID 2",
            "RAID 1",
            "RAID 6"
        ],
        "correct": "RAID 10"
    },
    {
        "id": 50,
        "question": "How many pins does a standard IDE controller have?",
        "options": [
            "33 Pins",
            "20 Pins",
            "40 Pins",
            "30 Pins"
        ],
        "correct": "40 Pins"
    },
    {
        "id": 51,
        "question": "What two cables does a Hard Disk require? (Choose two.)",
        "options": [
            "Power Cable",
            "AC Cable",
            "Data Cable",
            "Jumper Cable"
        ],
        "correct": "Power Cable, Data Cable"
    },
    {
        "id": 52,
        "question": "Sudden increase in voltage that lasts for a very short time period.",
        "options": [
            "Blackout",
            "Spike",
            "Surge",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "correct": "Spike"
    },
    {
        "id": 53,
        "question": "Runs continuously to protect against unauthorized communications to and from your computer.",
        "options": [
            "Antivirus",
            "Firewall",
            "Virus",
            "RDP"
        ],
        "correct": "Firewall"
    },
    {
        "id": 54,
        "question": "What are the two types of fault caused by electrostatic discharge? (Choose two.)",
        "options": [
            "Direct Fault",
            "Indirect Fault",
            "Latent Fault",
            "Unknown Fault"
        ],
        "correct": "Direct Fault, Latent Fault"
    },
    {
        "id": 55,
        "question": "Minimum number of drives required for RAID 6.",
        "options": [
            "3 Drives",
            "4 Drives",
            "2 Drives",
            "1 Drive"
        ],
        "correct": "4 Drives"
    },
    {
        "id": 56,
        "question": "PS/2 Port can be used for?",
        "options": [
            "External Hard Drive",
            "Speaker",
            "Printer",
            "Keyboard"
        ],
        "correct": "Keyboard"
    },
    {
        "id": 57,
        "question": "What does 'O' in OLED stand for?",
        "options": [
            "Original",
            "Organic",
            "Output",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "correct": "Organic"
    },
    {
        "id": 58,
        "question": "LCD stands for?",
        "options": [
            "Liquid Crystal Display",
            "Laser Crystal Display",
            "Light Crystal Display",
            "All of these"
        ],
        "correct": "Liquid Crystal Display"
    },
    {
        "id": 59,
        "question": "Information travels between components on the motherboard through:",
        "options": [
            "Flash Memory",
            "CMOS",
            "Bays",
            "Buses"
        ],
        "correct": "Buses"
    },
    {
        "id": 60,
        "question": "Which of the following is the system software?",
        "options": [
            "Azure",
            "OS",
            "PDF",
            "CMOS"
        ],
        "correct": "OS"
    },
    {
        "id": 61,
        "question": "Which is not the Display Output Port?",
        "options": [
            "HDMI",
            "DVI",
            "VDI",
            "VGA"
        ],
        "correct": "VDI"
    },
    {
        "id": 62,
        "question": "Which RAID technology uses Double Parity?",
        "options": [
            "RAID 1",
            "RAID 2",
            "RAID 5",
            "RAID 6"
        ],
        "correct": "RAID 6"
    },
    {
        "id": 63,
        "question": "Parallel Port can transmit?",
        "options": [
            "2 bit",
            "86 bit",
            "64 bit",
            "8 bit"
        ],
        "correct": "8 bit"
    },
    {
        "id": 64,
        "question": "RJ45 Port is used to connect?",
        "options": [
            "Mouse",
            "Printer",
            "Monitor",
            "Ethernet Cable"
        ],
        "correct": "Ethernet Cable"
    },
    {
        "id": 65,
        "question": "eSATA port is used to connect?",
        "options": [
            "External Monitor",
            "External Hard Drive",
            "External Power Supply",
            "External Speaker"
        ],
        "correct": "External Hard Drive"
    },
    {
        "id": 66,
        "question": "RFI stands for?",
        "options": [
            "Radio Fluctuation Induction",
            "Radio Frequency Interference",
            "Radio Feature Imbalance",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "correct": "Radio Frequency Interference"
    },
    {
        "id": 67,
        "question": "What do you use to clean Heat Sink?",
        "options": [
            "Vacuum Cleaner",
            "Hair Dryer",
            "Compressed Air",
            "Any of the above"
        ],
        "correct": "Compressed Air"
    },
    {
        "id": 68,
        "question": "Reduced voltage level of AC is referred to as?",
        "options": [
            "Blackout",
            "Burnout",
            "Overheat",
            "Brownout"
        ],
        "correct": "Brownout"
    },
    {
        "id": 69,
        "question": "SSD stands for?",
        "options": [
            "Solid State Drive",
            "Solid State Disk",
            "Super State Drive",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "correct": "Solid State Drive"
    }
    
]